DEVLIN BOOTH

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full stack software developer with experience developing with multiple different technologies. Detail-oriented, organized and meticulous employee. Works at fast pace to meet tight deadlines. Enthusiastic team player ready to contribute to company success. Complex problem-solver with analytical and driven mindset. Dedicated to achieving demanding development objectives while producing impeccable code. Smart professional with proven troubleshooting and debugging capabilities for resolving complex technical issues.

WORK HISTORY

Software Engineering Associate, 06/2022 - Current General Assembly, Remote

- Guided over 90 students through the rigorous transformational journey of becoming a full stack software developer.
- Provide hands-on instruction in a safe, supportive, and energetic environment; welcoming students with diverse needs and learning styles.
- Selected as part of the instructional team for the blended learning pilot program.
- Leverage strong communication skills while educating students in developing Full Stack applications

Software Engineering Apprentice, 11/2022 - 02/2023 App Academy, Remote

- 450 hour apprenticeship building upon existing knowledge as well as learning new tech!
- Completed over 1000 code challenges, projects, and course materials to strengthen core software engineering concepts.
- Utilized Mocha/Chai testing frameworks and assertion libraries to implement test driven development at unit, intergartion and End-2-End test levels.
- Added a plethora of tech to my already diverse arsenal of software tech tools.

Software Engineering Fellow, 12/2021 - 03/2022 General Assembly, Remote

- Hands-on experience w/ multiple programming languages, frameworks, libraries, and database types. Executed app planning via wire-framing, ERD-diagramming, and user-story implementation of features.
- Developed MERN Stack Application to bring book-lovers together.
- Created Django/Python/Postgresql Application for planning events, uploading recipes, and sharing / voting upon recipes for event.
- Project manager in three-person team Git-Hub workflow environment.

- Cos Angeles, CA 90046
- 5044306996
- adevlin.booth@gmail.com
- **Bold Profile**

LINKS:

- linkedin.com/in/devlin-booth/
- github.com/adevlinb
- devlin-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- Node.js
- React.js
- Express.js
- MongoDB
- Python
- Django
- PostgreSQL
- Sequelize
- Docker
- API Design

EDUCATION

Master of Arts, Landscape Architecture, 05/2011

Louisiana State University - Baton Rouge

Bachelor of Science, Urban Planning, 12/2007

University of New Orleans - New Orleans, LA